Hey guys, welcome back to our listening course.
Today we'll explore a learning method that helps
maximize your listening scores for the first question type: Completion.
This question has four main types, form completion, table completion, sentence completion, and summary completion.
In this video, we'll get to know two
question types, form completion and table completion,
which often appear in part one of the listening test.
They are considered the easiest types to boost the listening score.
For this type of question, the missing information that needs filling in can be names of
places and people, time, date, hour, phone number, and house address.
To handle this question type, we'll have six steps to follow.
Step one, read the instructions carefully and note
the word and number limit.
The instruction says, write no more than three words
and or a number for each answer.
This means the answer to be filled in is no more than three words and a number.
If you use more or less than the
word limit, your answer will be marked as incorrect.
So check the word limit carefully for each question.
Step two, read the title to identify
the information we need to focus on.
Here, the title of this question is Karate
Center Registration Form, so we can predict that
the content is about signing up for karate classes.
Step three, underline keywords.
In the previous lesson, we already learned how to identify keywords.
Keywords are words that play an important part
in a sentence, carrying the main content of that sentence.
Keywords are often nouns, verbs, and adjectives, and
not prepositions such as to, from, and at, or articles such as a, an, and the.
So what are the keywords in this form?
First, the keyword is in the title Karate and Registration.
Other keywords are name, date of birth, address,
phone number, experience, and medical.
In the last sentence, the keywords are how, you, here, us.
After underlining keywords, we'll move on to step four, predict the answer.
We need to predict which part of speech each gap needs.
Should it be a verb, a noun, an adjective, an adverb, or a number?
Let's take a look at these questions.
Question one needs a family or surname,
which will likely be spelled out in the recording.
In question two, we need to listen for
an address, which includes the name of the street or road.
We may expect both spellings of names and numbers in this blank.
In question three, you will need to listen for the rest of the phone number.
In question four, we are looking for a medical condition.
When you see this on a form,
you should prepare yourself to hear nouns or adjectives
related to health problems.
Common answers often include things like allergies, or
perhaps an injury like a back problem.
Listen carefully for the speaker mentioning anything
they suffer from, or any health issues they might have.
Remember to check your spelling carefully, as medical terms can sometimes be tricky.
Finally, for question five, the prompt asks, how did you hear about us?
This blank requires you to identify the source of information.
In the recording, this can usually be a specific channel of communication.
You should listen for keywords like advertisement, newspaper, social media, or perhaps a friend.
Have you got the information needed?
Let's move on to step five.
Listen to the recording and find the words
that have the same meaning or paraphrases.
This step is very important.
During the listening test, we need to find
paraphrases or words in the recording that have
the same meaning with keywords in the question.
And then step six, write down the answer
and don't forget to check the spelling.
Now let's listen carefully to the recording and write down the answers on your paper.
Good morning, Karama Karate Center.
How can I help you today?
Hi, I'd like to ask about your karate classes, please.
Of course.
Are you registering for you or your family members?
For me.
All right, sir.
First, I need to get your basic information.
May I have your name, please?
Yes, it's Philip Devon.
Is that D-E-V-O-N?
No, it's D-E-V-A-U-G-H-N.
Sorry, it's a bit complicated.
I'm Irish.
Got it.
Thank you.
And your date of birth?
It's the 31st of October, 1997.
Oh, it's on Halloween.
Yes.
Haha.
Now, could you give me your address?
Yes, I live at 1705 County Road 44.
Is that near Burlington Avenue?
Yes.
You make a left turn there and there's my house.
And your phone number, please?
It's plus 352-300-797516.
Great.
Have you ever taken martial arts classes before?
No, I haven't.
This will be my first time.
That's fine.
Do you have any medical history or conditions
that could affect your ability to participate in contact sports?
I sometimes get headaches, but they are usually because of work stress.
They won't affect my performance.
Thank you for letting me know.
If you ever feel unwell during practice, just let us know.
Last but not least, how did you hear about our center?
From a colleague, actually.
They recently started karate and recommended your center.
Do you by chance know Adrian Rodriguez?
Ah, yes.
He's in the blue belt class.
Wow, really?
Man, I don't know that he's that good.
Did you get all of them?
Now let's check the answers together.
Here's the transcript for today's recording.
Let's listen again and locate the answer.
Good morning, Karama Karate Center.
How can I help you today?
Hi, I'd like to ask about your karate classes, please.
Of course.
Are you registering for you or your family members?
For me.
All right, sir.
First, I need to get your basic information.
May I have your name, please?
Yes, it's Philip Devon.
Is that D-E-V-O-N?
No, it's D-E-V-A-U-G-H-N.
Sorry, it's a bit complicated.
I'm Irish.
Got it.
Thank you.
And your date of birth?
It's the 31st of October, 1997.
Oh, it's on Halloween.
Yes.
Now, could you give me your address?
I live at 1705 County Road 44.
Is that near Burlington Avenue?
Yes.
You make a left turn there and there's my house.
And your phone number, please?
It's plus 352-300-797516.
Great.
Have you ever taken martial arts classes before?
No, I haven't.
This will be my first time.
That's fine.
Do you have any medical history or conditions
that could affect your ability to participate in contact sports?
I sometimes get headaches, but they are usually because of work stress.
They won't affect my performance.
Thank you for letting me know.
If you ever feel unwell during practice, just let us know.
Last but not least, how did you hear about our center?
From a colleague, actually.
They recently started karate and recommended your center.
Do you by chance know Adrian Rodriguez?
Ah, yes.
He's in the blue belt class.
Wow, really?
Man, I don't know that he's that good.
As you can see for question one,
the answer is spelled out for you.
Listening to spelling in listening part one is
a skill you should practice to ensure
you don't lose points for these questions.
Question two can be quite tricky since
the name of the road is not spelled out in the recording.
Therefore, you should practice spelling proper names based on their pronunciation.
From the pronunciation as county, we can write
the name of the road as C-O -U-N-T-Y, similar to the word count.
Question three, the numbers are spelled out and
there is no correction of information in the recording.
Question four, when the receptionist asked about any
medical history or conditions, Philip mentioned that sometimes
he has headaches.
Make sure that you have an S at the end.
And question five, Philip mentioned that he heard
about the center from a colleague.
The word colleague is quite a long word
and can be tricky for some students.
Make sure to check your spelling carefully after
writing the answers.
Now, let's apply the same six steps to
the rest of the recording and complete this table.
First, from the requirement, we understand that
our answer in each blank cannot be longer than
two words and a number.
Step two, since this is the second half of the recording that we listened to earlier,
we already knew that the recording is about
a man named Philip calling to register for
classes at a karate center.
For step three, here are the keywords that I underlined.
Total, first, payment, class days, only, notes, go,
classes, cancellation, fee, dropout, rules, no food, drink, accept.
Now, it's your turn to do step four,
predicting the type of information in each blank.
Now, let's listen and write down the answers.
Now, let me just run through some more
important information regarding classes, tuition fees, and our policy.
All right.
For the beginner class with no prior training, the fee is $60.
OK.
Does that include uniforms as well?
No, you have to pay another $45 for that.
So, in total, I have to pay $105, right?
Yes, that's correct.
Just a note, we don't accept cash payments
and you must pay all the fees at
least one week before your class starts.
You can pay by credit card or bank transfer.
That's fine.
I'll pay by bank transfer.
Now, about your class schedule, the beginner class is from 6 p.m. to 8 p .m. on Tuesday and Friday.
I am afraid I can't make it on Tuesday.
I have other plans that day.
That's not a problem, but I would recommend
you attend extra classes on the weekend to catch up with your classmates.
This way, you won't fall behind.
That sounds good.
I'll try to make time.
One more thing.
If you decide to drop out of the
class in the middle of the season, there's a $35 cancellation fee.
This is because it's difficult for us to replace students once the season starts.
I understand.
Also, during the practice, you won't be allowed to bring food or drink in the class.
Not even a water bottle?
That's OK to bring.
If you have any more questions, feel free to ask.
No, that's all for now.
Thank you very much.
Great job, guys.
Let's check the answers together.
Here is the transcript of the recording.
In question 6, you may hear the receptionist
mentioning $60 at first, but that is the fee without uniform.
The correct answer is mentioned by Philip later, $105.
The important keyword here is total, which appears
in both the table and the transcript.
In question 7, the receptionist said Tuesday and
Friday, but since Philip cannot make it on
Tuesday, the correct answer is Friday.
Tuesday is a distractor.
Question 8, the correct answer is the weekend.
Remember to include the, since it is the grammatically correct one.
Question 9, you can either write the number 35 or spell out the letters.
Make sure to not write the word dollars
because the dollar symbol is already there.
And the last one, our correct answer is water bottle.
Great job, everyone.
So, remember that for form and table completion,
checking spelling and grammar after answering is very important.
Hooray!
We've already grasped how to handle two question types, form completion and table completion.
Let's review what we've learned today.
First, the completion question has four main types,
form completion, table completion, sentence completion, and summary completion.
Next, we'll follow these six steps to do
the form completion and the table completion.
That's it for today's lesson.
Don't forget to do the exercises and practice
what you've learned regularly.
Goodbye and see you in the next lesson.
Thank you.